Preliminary Guide to the Durham Central Labor Union Records, ca. 1921-1971 RL.00340
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Central Labor Union records
circa 1921-1971
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Central Labor Union
RL.00340
45 Linear Feet
6602 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library received this collection as a purchase, 1999.
Historical Note
The Durham Central Labor Union is the umbrella organization for Durham labor unions.
The records came from the upper floor of the St. Luke Apostolic Church of Jesus Christ building, formerly Durham's Central Union Hall (or Labor Temple).
Collection Overview
Minutes, financial records, correspondence, memorabilia, and other materials from various Durham labor unions and their local umbrella organization, the Durham Central Labor Union. Accession 2001-0007 has been interfiled with accession 1999-0158.
The individual unions include: Tobacco Workers International Union Local 183; International Association of Bridge, Structural, and Ornamental Iron Workers Local 636; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 553; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 522; Painters and Decorators Local 678; Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 585, Office Employees International Union Local 84; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, and Helpers Local 81; and Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterer's International Union Local 10.
Labor unions -- North Carolina; Memorabilia; Labor unions -- United States; Labor unions -- North Carolina -- Finance; Tobacco Workers International Union. Local No. 183; Office Employees International Union. Local 84; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, and Helpers. Local No. 81; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Local No. 553; International Association of Bridge, Structural, and Ornamental Iron Workers Local No. 636; Durham Central Labor Union; Durham Central Labor Union; Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America. Local No. 678; Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union. Local No. 10; United Association of Plumbers and Steam Fitters of the United States and Canada. Local No. 585; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local No. 522
- Accessions 1999-0158 and 2001-0007
  - Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 183 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    See also Oversize.
    - Certificates of Appreciation for 20-year union members, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1945-1947 (Box 1)
    - Officer election and delegate election ballots, 1967; 1970; 1971 (Box 1)
  - International Association of Bridge, Structural, and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 636 (Box 2)
    - Cash Books, 1941-1948 (Box 2)
    - Financial Ledgers, 1942; 1946-1957 (Box 2)
    - Daybooks, 1941 March -1953 August (Box 3)
    - Daybooks, 1953 September -1956 March (Box 4)
    - Membership Records, 1957-1967 (Box 5)
    - Membership Records, 1957-1967 (Box 6)
    - Check Stubs, 1953-1962 (Box 7)
    - Financial Statements, 1948-1960 (Box 7)
    - Files and Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 553 (Box 8)
    - Receipt Books, 1942-1968 (Box 8)
    - Receipt Books, 1942-1968 (Box 9)
    - Receipt Books, 1942-1968 (Box 10)
    - Receipt Books, 1942-1968 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1934-1940; 1942-1947; 1949-1950; 1954-1956 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous files; election returns, correspondence, etc. (Box 13)
    - Financial Records (Box 14)
      - Deposits and expenditures, 1942-1946 (Box 14)
      - Ledgers, 1941-1945 (Box 14)
      - Records, 1949-1950 (Box 14)
      - Check Stubs, 1941-1949; 1951-1959 (Box 14)
      - Health Insurance Receipts, 1964-1968 (Box 14)
      - Receipts for International Union dues, 1955-1962 (Box 14)
      - Financial Statements, 1947-1962 (Box 14)
  - United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 522 (Box 15)
    - Members' Records, 1947-1954 (Box 15)
    - Financial Records (Box 16)
      - Daybooks, 1941 October -1943 January; 1948 September -1950 September; 1951 February -1958 September (Box 16)
      - Quarterly account sheets, 1950-1959 (incomplete) (Box 16)
      - Small Receipt Books, 1958 October -1959 December (Box 16)
      - Large receipt book, 1950 January -1951 February (Box 16)
      - Expenses records, 1951-1952 (Box 16)
      - Individual members' dues books, ca. 1948-1957, 50 books (Box 16)
      - Check Stubs, 1948-1954; 1961-1962 (Box 17)
      - Cancelled checks and deposit slips, 1958-1959 (Box 17)
    - Membership applications, 1946-1952 (Box 17)
    - Arrears notices, 1955-1957 (Box 17)
    - Minutes, 1949-1955 (Box 18)
    - Ballots (officer elections), ca. 1957-1959 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous files; Correspondence, contracts, etc. (Box 18)
  - Painters and Decorators, Local 678 (Box 19)
    - Financial records
      - Monthly financial reports, 1946-1952 (Box 19)
      - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1956-1967 (Box 19)
      - Ledgers, 1942-1949; 1952-1953 (Box 19)
      - Check Stubs, 1951 April -1951 November; 1952 July -1952 December (Box 19)
      - Receipts, 1940 December -1941 February; 1941 December -1942 January (Box 19)
    - Daybooks, 1943-1967 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, 1940-1950 (Box 21)
    - Ledger, 1940-1944 (Box 21)
    - Rolodex (Box 21)
    - Contracts and forms, ca 1955 (Box 21)
    - Membership applications, 1952 (Box 21)
  - Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 585 (Box 22)
    - Small receipt books, 1951-1952 (Box 22)
    - Weekly record report envelopes, 1951 December 19-1952 January 25 (Box 22)
  - Office Employees International Union, Local 84 (Box 23)
    - Member additions and removals, 1947-1948 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Contracts, 1947 (Box 23)
    - Union representation authorization cards, 1943 (Box 23)
    - Banking information, 1945; 1947 (Box 23)
    - Roster of Office Employees' Local unions, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Financial Records
      - Ledgers, 1943-1950 (Box 23)
      - Daybooks, 1943-1946 (Box 23)
      - International Union Dues
        - Receipts, 1943-1946; 1950-1951 (Box 23)
        - Information (Box 23)
      - Monthly financial reports, 1943-1945 (Box 23)
      - Check stubs 1944-1949 (Box 23)
      - Receipts, 1943-1944; 1948-1950 (scattered) (Box 23)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, and Helpers, Local 81 (Box 24)
    - Application blanks, 1941-1951 (Box 24)
    - Contracts, expiration date 1950 April (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, ca. 1940-1950 (Box 24)
    - Internal payment notes, 1941 (Box 24)
    - Withdrawal cards, 1947-1950 (Box 24)
    - Union representation authorization cards, 1943-1950 (Box 24)
    - Members' dues books, ca. 1949 (Box 24)
    - Minutes, 1941-1946 (Box 24)
    - Tax information, ca. 1944-1946 (Box 24)
    - Utility bills, 1946-1948 (Box 24)
    - Financial records
      - Receipt stubs, 1941 (Box 24)
      - Business agents' collections, 1946-1947 (Box 24)
      - Receipts from National, 1942-1947 (Box 24)
      - Checks and checkbooks, 1944-1949 (Box 25)
      - Bank statements, 1941 (Box 25)
      - Cash Book, 1941-1945 (Box 25)
      - Monthly reports, 1948-1949 (Box 25)
  - Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union, Local 10 (Box 26)
    - Ledger, 1939-1943 (Box 26)
    - Duplicate cash records, 1943-1946 (Box 26)
    - Job referral forms, 1942 (Box 26)
    - Receipt stubs, 1948-1949 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous files, 1942-1948 (Box 26)
    - Membership applications, 1937-1942; 1947; 1949-1950 (Box 26)
    - Shop Stewards' reports, 1942 (Box 26)
  - Durham Central Labor Union (Box 27)
    See also oversize.
    - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 27)
    - Minutes, 1927-1945; 1960-1963 (Box 27)
    - Receipts, 1933-1959 (Box 28)
    - Bankbooks, 1956-1957 (Box 28)
    - Daybook, 1948-1949 (Box 28)
    - Cash books, 1937-1939; 1944-1953; 1955-1962 (Box 28)
    - Financial record, 1950-1953 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 28)
    - Photograph block negatives (Box 28)
    - Wooden gavel (Box 28)
    - Pen (Box 28)
    - 48-star American flag (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous ledgers, minutes, etc. from unions not affiliated with the Durham Central Labor Union (Box 29)
  - Bricklayers' Memorial Plaque to Union members in WWII (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Durham Central Labor Union Financial record, 1952-1956 (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Voters for Better Government Daybook (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Durham Central Labor Union, Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 31 (Oversize))
  - Tobacco Workers' Election results, 1970; 1971 (Box 31 (Oversize))
  - Metal die for Durham Central Labor Union stamp, undated (Box 32)
  - Tobacco Workers' Election results, 1970; 1971 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Labor Directory Wall Plaque (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Brickmakers, Masons, Plasterers' International Union of America, Durham Local, Charter, [1926] (Oversize-folder 1)